[
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm  ceFace(a, b) , where a and b are natural numbers  (1 ≤ a, b ≤ 10000  at the initial call ). The algorithm  ceFace(a, b)  returns True  if and only if : ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "a and b have the same number of digits"
            },
            {
                "B": "a and b are equal"
            },
            {
                "C": "a and b are written using  the same digits, but in different  sequence"
            },
            {
                "D": "the last digit of  a is equal with the last digit of  b"
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm ceFace(a, b):\n    While (a MOD 10 = b MOD 10) AND (a ≠ 0) AND (b ≠ 0) execute\n        a ← a DIV 10\n        b ← b DIV 10\n    EndWhile\n    If ((a = 0) AND (b = 0)) then\n        return True\n    else\n        return False\n    EndIf\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "B",
        "index": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm  f(a, n)  where  n is a natural number (2 ≤ n ≤ 10000) and a is an array of  n natural numbers  (a[1], a[2], ..., a[n], -100 ≤ a[i] ≤ 100, for i = 1, 2, ..., n). The local variable b is an array . Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "The algorithm returns the sum of  all elements of array a."
            },
            {
                "B": "The algorithm returns the sum of the last two elements  of array a."
            },
            {
                "C": "The algorithm returns the last element  of array  a."
            },
            {
                "D": "The algorithm returns the sum of the last  n – 1 element s of array  a.\n2"
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm f(a, n):\ni ← 2\nb[1] ← a[1]\nWhile i ≤ n execute\nb[i] ← b[i - 1] + a[i]\ni ← i + 1\nEndWhile\nreturn b[n]\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "A",
        "index": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following algorithms returns the number of distinct prime factors of a given natural number  n  (5 < n < 105 at the initial call ). ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "// The length of array prime  is n\n// prime[i] is True, if\n// the number  i is prime and False\n// otherwise\nAlgorithm nrFactoriPrimi_A(n, prime):\n    d ← 2\n    nr ← 0\n    p ← 0\n    While n > 0 execute\n        While n MOD d = 0 execute\n            p ← p + 1\n            n ← n DIV d\n        EndWhile\n        If p ≠ 0 then\n            nr ← nr + 1\n        EndIf\n        d ← d + 1\n        While prime[d]  = False execute\n            d ← d + 1\n        EndWhile\n        p ← 0\n    EndWhile\n    return nr\nEndAlgorithm"
            },
            {
                "C": "Algorithm nrFactoriPrimi_ C(n):\nnr ← 0\nFor d ← 2, n execute\nIf n MOD d = 0 then\nnr ← nr + 1\nEndIf\nWhile n MOD d = 0 execute\nn ← n DIV d\nEndWhile\nEndFor\nreturn nr\nEndAlgorithm"
            },
            {
                "B": "Algorithm nrFactoriPrimi_ B(n):\n    d ← 2\n    nr ← 0\n    While n > 1 execute\n        p ← 0\n        While n MOD d = 0 execute\n            p ← p + 1\n            n ← n DIV d\n        EndWhile\n        If p > 0 then\n            nr ← nr + 1\n        EndIf\n        If d = 2 then\n            d ← d + 1\n        else\n            d ← d + 2\n        EndIf\n    EndWhile\n    return nr\nEndAlgorithm"
            },
            {
                "D": "Algorithm nrFactoriPrimi_D(n):\nnr ← 0\nd ← 2\nWhile d * d ≤ n  execute\nIf n MOD d = 0 then\nnr ← nr + 1\nEndIf\nWhile n MOD d = 0 execute\nn ← n DIV d\nEndWhile\nd ← d + 1\nEndWhile\nreturn nr\nEndAlgorithm"
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "BC",
        "index": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm ceFace(n, m) , where  n is a natural number (0 ≤ n ≤ 1000) with the last digit not equal to  0. What is the result of the call ceFace(n, 0) ? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "0 (regardless of the value of  n)"
            },
            {
                "B": "n (regardless of the value of n)"
            },
            {
                "C": "The sum of the digits of  n"
            },
            {
                "D": "The reverse of number  n\n 3"
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm ceFace(n, m):\n    If n = 0 then\n        return m\n    else\n        return ceFace(n DIV 10, m * 10 + n MOD 10)\n    EndIf\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "D",
        "index": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm  f(x, n)  where  n is a natural  number  (2 ≤ n ≤ 10000), and x is an array of n natural numbers  (x[1], x[2], ..., x[n], 1 ≤ x[i] ≤ 10000, for i = 1, 2, ..., n). Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "The algorithm returns False  if two random element s of the array  x are distinct ."
            },
            {
                "B": "The algorithm returns False  if two random elements of the array x are equal."
            },
            {
                "C": "The algorithm returns False  if two consecutive elements of the array x are equal ."
            },
            {
                "D": "The algorithm returns False  if the first two elements of the array x are equal ."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm f(x, n):\nFor i = 1, n – 1 execute\nIf x[i] = x[i + 1] then\nreturn False\nEndIf\nEndFor\nreturn True\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "CD",
        "index": 5
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm  f(x, n)  where  x and n are natural  numbers  (0 ≤ n ≤ 10000, 0 < x ≤ 10000) . Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "The algorithm returns x at the power of  n."
            },
            {
                "B": "If on line 7 , we replace  n MOD 2 with m MOD 2, then the algorithm return s x at the power of  n."
            },
            {
                "C": "Because of the recursive call on line 6, the lines  7, 8, 9, 10 will never be execu ted."
            },
            {
                "D": "The algorithm returns  1 if n is an even number or  it returns x if n is an odd number ."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm f(x, n):\n2.     If n = 0 then\n3.         return 1\n4.     EndIf\n5.     m ← n DIV 2\n6.     p ← f(x, m)\n7.     If n MOD 2 = 0 then\n8.         return p * p\n9.     EndIf\n10.    return x * p * p\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "A",
        "index": 6
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering that all multipli cation s and division s require a constant  amount of time , what can be stated about the time complexity of the  algorithm  considered in problem statement 6? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "The time complexity depend s on parameters  x and n."
            },
            {
                "B": "The time complexity does not depend on the parameter  x."
            },
            {
                "C": "The time complexity is  O(log log n)."
            },
            {
                "D": "The time complexity is logarithmic based on the parameter n (O(log n))."
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "BD",
        "index": 7
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm  afișare(n ), where  n is a natural number  (1 ≤ n ≤ 10000) . What will be displayed for the call afișare(1000) ? 4 ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "1000 2000 4000"
            },
            {
                "B": "1000 2000 4000 4000 2000 1000"
            },
            {
                "C": "1000 2000 4000 2000 1000"
            },
            {
                "D": "1000 2000 2000 1000"
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm afișare(n):\nIf n ≤ 4000 then\nWrite n, \" \"\nafișare(2 * n)\nWrite n, \" \"\nEndIf\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "B",
        "index": 8
    },
    {
        "question": "Which could be the values of an array so that, applying  the binary search method for value  36, it will be successively compared with  values  12, 24, 36: ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "[2, 4, 7, 12, 24, 36, 50]"
            },
            {
                "B": "[2, 4, 8, 9, 12, 16, 20, 24, 36, 67]"
            },
            {
                "C": "[4, 8, 9, 12, 16, 24, 36]"
            },
            {
                "D": "[12, 24, 36, 42, 54, 66]"
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "BC",
        "index": 9
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following mathematical expressions are equivalent to  x MOD y for all strictly positive natural numbers x and y (0 < x, y ≤ 10000) ? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "x DIV y"
            },
            {
                "B": "x – (y * (x DIV y))"
            },
            {
                "C": "x – (x * (x DIV y))"
            },
            {
                "D": "x DIV y + y DIV x"
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "B",
        "index": 10
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider variab le n that stores a natural  number . Which of the following expressions is True if and only if n is divisible  by 2 and by 3 ? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "(n DIV 2 = 0) OR (n DIV 3 ≠ 0)"
            },
            {
                "B": "(n MOD 3 = 2) OR (n MOD 2 = 3)"
            },
            {
                "C": "(n MOD 2 ≠ 1) AND (n MOD 3 = 0)"
            },
            {
                "D": "(n MOD 2 = 0) AND (n MOD 3 ≠ 1)"
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "C",
        "index": 11
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider variable n that stores a natural number.  Which of the following expressions is True if and only if n is divisible  by 2 and by 3 ? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "(n MOD 2) - (n MOD 3) = 0"
            },
            {
                "B": "(n MOD 2) - (n MOD 3) < 0"
            },
            {
                "C": "(n MOD 2) + (n MOD 3) > 0"
            },
            {
                "D": "(n MOD 2) + (n MOD 3) = 0"
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "D",
        "index": 12
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm f(n), where  n is a natural  number  (1 ≤ n ≤ 100). The o perator ”/” stands for real division  (ex. 3 / 2 =  1,5). State the effect of the  algorithm . ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "Evaluates the expression  1/1 ∗ 1/2 ∗ 1/3 ∗ ... ∗ 1/n"
            },
            {
                "B": "Evaluates the expression  1/1 ∗ 1/(1∗2) ∗ 1/(1∗2∗3) ∗ ... ∗ 1/(1∗2∗3∗…∗n)"
            },
            {
                "C": "Evaluates the expression  1/1 ∗ 1/(1+2) ∗ 1/(1+2+3) ∗ ... ∗ 1/(1+2+3+…+ n)"
            },
            {
                "D": "Evaluates the expression  1/1 + 1/(1 ∗2) + 1/(1∗2∗3) + ... + 1/(1 ∗2∗3∗…∗n)"
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm f(n):\n    s ← 0; p ← 1;\n    For i ← 1, n execute\n        s ← s + i\n        p ← p * (1 / s)\n    EndFor\n    return p\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "C",
        "index": 13
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm  prelucrare(s1, lung1, s2, lung2) , where  s1 and s2 are two arrays of characters of length  lung 1, respectively  lung 2 (1 ≤ lung 1, lung 2 ≤ 1000). The two strings contain only characters  having  ASCII codes in the interval  [1, 125]. The local variable  x is an array . Let us consider the algorithm  ascii(s, i ), which returns  the ASCII code of the i-th character of array  s. 5 What is the result of the algorithm? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "The algorithm returns  True  if the arrays of characters s1 and s2 have the same length and  False\notherwise ."
            },
            {
                "B": "The algorithm returns  True if the arrays of characters s1 and s2 contain the same characters\nhaving the same corresponding frequency  and False  otherwise ."
            },
            {
                "C": "The algorithm returns  True  if in both arrays of characters s1 and s2 all characters having ASCII\ncodes in the interval [1, 125] appear and False  otherwise ."
            },
            {
                "D": "The algorithm returns  True  if the two arrays of characters  s1 and s2 use different characters and\nFalse  otherwise ."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm prelucrare(s1, lung1, s2, lung2):\nFor i = 1, 125 execute\nx[i] ← 0\nEndFor\nFor i = 1, lung1 execute\nx[ascii(s1, i)] ← x[ascii(s1, i)] + 1\nEndFor\nFor i = 1, lung2 execute\nx[ascii(s2, i)] ← x[ascii(s2, i)] - 1\nEndFor\nok ← True\nFor i = 1, 125 execute\nIf x[i] ≠ 0 then\nok ← False\nEndIf\nEndFor\nreturn ok\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "B",
        "index": 14
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the result of converting the binary number  100101100111 into base  10? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "2407"
            },
            {
                "B": "2408"
            },
            {
                "C": "1203"
            },
            {
                "D": "None of the answers"
            },
            {
                "A": ","
            },
            {
                "B": ","
            },
            {
                "C": ""
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "A",
        "index": 15
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider an array  a of n natural numbers  (a[1], a[2], …, a[n]), the natural  number  n (1 ≤ n ≤ 10000) and a natural number  x. Which of the following code sequence s display  the position having the minim al index  where the value  x is situated in the array  a, or displays -1 if x is not found  in a? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "i ← 1\nWhile (i ≤ n) AND (a[i] = x) execute\ni ← i + 1\nEndWhile\nIf i ≤ n then\nWrite i\nelse\nWrite –1\nEndIf"
            },
            {
                "C": "i ← 1\nWhile (i ≤ n) AND (a[i] = x) execute\ni ← i + 1\nEndWhile\nIf i = n + 1 then\nWrite i\nelse\nWrite –1\nEndIf"
            },
            {
                "B": "i ← 1\nWhile (i ≤ n) AND (a[i] ≠ x) execute\ni ← i + 1\nEndWhile\nIf i = n + 1 then\nWrite i\nelse\nWrite –1\nEndIf"
            },
            {
                "D": "i ← 1\nWhile (i ≤ n) AND (a[i] ≠ x) execute\ni ← i + 1\nEndWhile\nIf i ≤ n then\nWrite i\nelse\nWrite –1\nEndIf\n6"
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "D",
        "index": 16
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider  the algorithm f(x), where  x is an integer : For which value of x does the algorit hm return the value  4? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "13369"
            },
            {
                "B": "21369"
            },
            {
                "C": "4"
            },
            {
                "D": "1233"
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm f(x):\n    If x = 0 then\n        return 0\n    else\n        If x MOD 3 = 0 then\n            return f(x DIV 10) + 1\n        else\n            return f(x DIV 10)\n        EndIf\n    EndIf\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "B",
        "index": 17
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm  f(n, i, j)  where  n, i and j are natural numbers  (1 ≤ n, i, j  ≤ 10000 at the initial call ). What will be displayed upon the execution of the call  f(15, 3, 10) ? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "*000000"
            },
            {
                "B": "*0#000"
            },
            {
                "C": "*0#0000"
            },
            {
                "D": "*0000000"
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm f(n, i, j):\nIf i > j then\nWrite '*'\nelse\nIf n MOD i = 0 then\nf(n, i - 1, j)\nelse\nIf n DIV i ≠ j then\nf(n, i + 1, j – 1)\nWrite '0'\nelse\nf(n, i + 2, j – 2)\nWrite '#'\nEndIf\nEndIf\nEndIf\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "B",
        "index": 18
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider algorithm ceFace(n, x) , where n is a natural number (1 ≤ n ≤ 100) and x is an array of n natural numbers ( x[1], x[2], …, x[n]). What will be the new content of array x after executing the algorithm if  n = 6 and x = [5, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1 ]?  7   ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "[1, 1, 2, 1, 3, 5 ]"
            },
            {
                "B": "[1, 1, 1, 2, 3, 5 ]"
            },
            {
                "C": "[5, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1 ]"
            },
            {
                "D": "None of the other options is correct."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm ceFace(n, x):\n    For i = 1, n execute\n        c ← x[i]\n        x[i] ← x[n – i + 1]\n        x[n – i + 1] ← c\n    EndFor\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "C",
        "index": 19
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm  what(n) , where  n is a natural number  (1 ≤ n ≤ 1000  at the initial call). Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "The algorithm returns  True  if and only if  eithe r n can be written using  only the digit 3, or n can\nbe written using  only the digit 7"
            },
            {
                "B": "The algorithm returns False  if n contains at least an even digit"
            },
            {
                "C": "The algorithm returns False  if and only if  n contains at least one digit c where  c ≠ 3 and c ≠ 7"
            },
            {
                "D": "The algorithm returns True if and only if  n does not contain any digit from the set  {0, 1, 2, 4,\n5, 6, 8, 9}\n`"
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm what(n):\nIf n = 0 then\nreturn True\nEndIf\nIf (n MOD 10 = 3) OR (n MOD 10 = 7) then\nreturn what(n DIV 10)\nelse\nreturn False\nEndIf\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "BCD",
        "index": 20
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm  calcul(x, n) , where  x and n are natural numb ers (1 ≤ x ≤ 10000, 1 ≤ n ≤ 10000), and x ≤ n. Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "If x = 2 and n = 5, then the algorithm returns 10."
            },
            {
                "B": "The algorithm returns  the number of subsets having x elements from the set  {1, 2, …, n}."
            },
            {
                "C": "The algorithm returns the number of partial permutations of n element s taken x at a time ."
            },
            {
                "D": "The algorithm returns the number of combinations of n elements  taken x at a time ."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm calcul(x, n):\n    b ← 1\n    For i ← 1, n – x execute\n        b ← b * i\n    EndFor\n    a ← b\n    For i ← n - x + 1, n execute\n        a ← a * i\n    EndFor\n    return a DIV b\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "C",
        "index": 21
    },
    {
        "question": "At a farm there are chickens and rabbits, each chicken has two legs and each rabbit has four legs . The total number of heads is  n and the total number  of leg s is m (0 ≤ n, m ≤ 104). Which of the following algorithms returns  True  and displays  all possible pairs of number s of chickens and rabbits at the farm , or returns False  if there are no solutions ?  8   ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "Algorithm ferma_A(n, m):\nfound = False\nFor i ← 0, n execute\nj ← n - i\nIf 2 * i + 4 * j = m then\nfound ← True\nWrite i, ' ', j\nWrite newline\nEndIf\nEndFor\nreturn found\nEndAlgorithm"
            },
            {
                "B": "Algorithm ferma_B(n, m):\n    found ← False\n    For i ← 0, n execute\n        For j ← 0, n execute\n            If 2 * i + 4 * j = m AND\ni + j = n then\n                found ← True\n                Write i, ' ', j\n                Write newline\n            EndIf\n        EndFor\n    EndFor\n    return found\nEndAlgorithm"
            },
            {
                "C": "Algorithm ferma_C(n, m):\nfound ← False\nFor i ← 0, n execute\nFor j ← 0, n - i execute\nIf 2 * i + 4 * j = m AND\ni + j = n then\nfound ← True\nWrite i, ' ', j\nWrite newline\nEndIf\nEndFor\nEndFor\nreturn found\nEndAlgorithm"
            },
            {
                "D": "Algorithm ferma_D(n, m):\n    found ← False\n    For i ← 0, n execute\n        For j ← 0, i execute\n            If 2 * i + 4 * j = m AND\ni + j = n then\n                found ← True\n                Write i, ' ', j\n                Write newline\n            EndIf\n        EndFor\n    EndFor\n    return found\nEndAlgorithm"
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "ABC",
        "index": 22
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider  a natural number  n, which can be written as the product of three natural numbers  a, b, c, (n = a * b * c). Which of the following expressions  has as result the remainder of the division  of n by the natural number  d (1 ≤ n, a, b, c, d ≤ 10000) ? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "(a MOD d) * b * c"
            },
            {
                "B": "((a MOD d) * (b MOD d) * (c MOD d)) MOD d"
            },
            {
                "C": "(a MOD d) * (b MOD d) * (c MOD d)"
            },
            {
                "D": "(a DIV d) * (b DIV d) * (c DIV d)"
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "B",
        "index": 23
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm  det(a, n, m) , where  a is an array of  n natural numbers  (a[1], a[2], ..., a[n] if n ≥ 1) or an empty array if  n = 0. n and m are natural number s (0 ≤ n ≤ 100 , 0 ≤ m ≤ 106). Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "The algorithm returns  True if array a contains  a pair o f numbers having their sum equal to m."
            },
            {
                "B": "The algorithm always returns  False ."
            },
            {
                "C": "The algorithm returns  False if n = 0."
            },
            {
                "D": "Lines 2, ..., 10 of t he algorithm sort array  a in ascending order ."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm det(a, n, m):\n2.     For i ← 1, n – 1 execute\n3.         For j ← i + 1, n execute\n4.             If a[i] > a[j] then\n5.                 tmp ← a[i]\n6.                 a[i] ← a[j]\n7.                 a[j] ← tmp\n8.             EndIf\n9.         EndFor\n10.     EndFor\n11.     i ← 1\n12.     j ← n\n13.     b ← False\n14.     While i < j execute\n15.         If a[i] + a[j] = m then\n16.             b ← True\n17.         EndIf  9\n18.         If a[i] + a[j] < m then\n19.             i ← i + 1\n20.         else\n21.             j ← j - 1\n22.         EndIf\n23.     EndWhile\n24.     return b\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "ACD",
        "index": 24
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm  magic(n, a) , where  a is an array  of n natural numbers  (a[1], a[2], ..., a[n], 1 ≤ n ≤ 10000). Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "For magic(5, [2, 5, 4, 5, 4])  the algorithm returns  False ."
            },
            {
                "B": "The algorithm indicates if there are duplicates in the array a, if and only if  array  a is sorted\nascending/ descending ."
            },
            {
                "C": "For magic(9, [1, 2, 3, 4, 4, 5, 6, 7, 9])  the algorithm returns  True."
            },
            {
                "D": "For magic(5, [9, 5, 5, 2, 4])  the algorithm returns  True."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm magic(n, a):\n    If n < 2 then\n        return False\n    EndIf\n    For i ← 2, n execute\n        If a[i – 1] = a[i] then\n            return True\n        EndIf\n    EndFor\n    return False\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "ACD",
        "index": 25
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm  f(n, a, b, c)  where  n is a natural number  (n ≤ 20) and a, b, c three integer numbers . What is the return value of the call  f(n, 1, 1, 2) ? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "2n+1 – 1"
            },
            {
                "B": "n"
            },
            {
                "C": "20 + 21 + 22 + ... + 2n"
            },
            {
                "D": "2n+1\n\n10"
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm f(n, a, b, c):\nIf n = 0 then\nreturn 1\nelse\nreturn f(n - 1, a * a, b + 1, c * 2) +  f(n - 1, a - 1, b * b, c + 1) + 1\nEndIf\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "AC",
        "index": 26
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithms  f(n, p)  and g(n), where  n and p are initially natural numbers  (1 ≤ n, p ≤ 106 at the initial call ). Algorithm f(n, p):     If n = 0 then         return 1     EndIf     If n > 0 AND n ≥ p then         c ← 0         If g(p) = True then             c ← c + f(n - p, p + 1)         EndIf         return c + f(n, p + 1)     EndIf     return 0 EndAlgorithm Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "The algorithm  g(n) returns  True  if n is prime and False  otherwise ."
            },
            {
                "B": "The call  f(n, 2)  returns the number of distinct ways of writing n as a sum of at least one term\nof distinct prime numbers in strictly ascending  order ."
            },
            {
                "C": "The call  f(n, 2)  returns the sum of the prime divisors of n."
            },
            {
                "D": "The calls  f(n, 1 ) and f(n, 2)  will return the same result , regardless of  n."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm g(n):\n    If n < 2 then\n        return False\n    EndIf\n    i ← 2\n    While i * i ≤ n execute\n        If n MOD i = 0 then\n            return False\n        EndIf\n        i ← i + 1\n    EndWhile\n    return True\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "ABD",
        "index": 27
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorith m AlexB(value, n, k, p) , where  value  is an array of  n natural numbers (value [1], value [2], ..., value [n]), and n, k and p are natural numbers . Initially the array  value  has n elements equal  to zero. The algorithm  afișare(value, n)  displays the array  value  on a single line . What will be displayed  on the 10th  line, if n = 5 and the algorithm is called like:  AlexB(value, 5, 1, 0) . ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "1 5 2 3 4"
            },
            {
                "B": "1 5 4 0 4"
            },
            {
                "C": "5 5 5 5 5"
            },
            {
                "D": "1 2 5 4 3"
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm AlexB(value, n, k, p):\np ← p + 1\nvalue[k] ← p\nIf p = n then\nafișare(value, n)\nelse\nFor i ← 1, n execute\nIf value[i] = 0 then\nAlexB(value, n, i, p)\nEndIf\nEndFor\nEndIf\np ← p - 1\nvalue[k] ← 0\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "A",
        "index": 28
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm  f(n) where  n is a natural number  (1 ≤ n ≤ 10000  at the initial call ).  11  The & operator  is the bitwise  AND operator ; the truth table is : & 0 1 0 0 0 1 0 1  Example : 2 & 7 in binary : 010 & 111 = 010 which is  2 in base  10. 6 & 1 in binary : 110 & 001 = 000 which  is 0 in base  10. Which of the following statements are NOT true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "If n is a power of  2, then f(n) returns value  1."
            },
            {
                "B": "If n >16 and n < 32, then f(n) returns a value  from  the {2, 3, 4,  5} set."
            },
            {
                "C": "The algorithm returns the number of even numbers strictly smaller than  n."
            },
            {
                "D": "The algorithm returns the number of odd numbers smaller than n."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm f(n):\n    c ← 0\n    If n ≠ 0 then\n        c ← c + 1\n        n ← n & (n - 1)       // bitwise AND\n        While n ≠ 0 execute\n            c ← c + 1\n            n ← n & (n - 1)   // bitwise AND\n        EndWhile\n    EndIf\n    return c\nEndAlgoritm",
        "correct_answers": "CD",
        "index": 29
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider algorithm calcul(v, n) , where n is a non zero natural number (1 ≤ n ≤ 10000) and v is an array of n integer numbers ( v[1], v[2], ..., v[n]). The instruction return x, y returns the pair of values ( x, y). Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "If the array contains only one element, the algorithm returns 0, -1"
            },
            {
                "B": "If n = 2 and the array’s  two elements are symmetric with respect to 0 (for example -5, 5), the\nresult will be -1, 1"
            },
            {
                "C": "If n = 2 and the array’s  two elements have  consecutive values  (for example 3, 4) , the\nalgorithm will always return the values 1, 2"
            },
            {
                "D": "One of the numbers returned by the algorithm represents the length of the longest sequence\ncontaining equal values from the second half of the array for any even number n > 1"
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm calcul(v, n):\ni ← n DIV 2 + 1\nj ← i + 1\nk ← i\np ← j\nWhile j ≤ n execute\nWhile (j ≤ n) AND (v[i] = v[j]) execute\nj ← j + 1\nEndWhile\nIf j - i > p - k then\nk ← i\np ← j\nEndIf\ni ← j\nj ← j + 1\nEndWhile\nIf j - i > p - k then\nk ← i\np ← j\nEndIf\nreturn p - k, k\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "CD",
        "index": 30
    }
]